Welcome to Mental Health Monday. So
happy that you guys are here with us.
Good to see you, Dr. White. always good
to see uh all of our viewing audience as
well. And so I know we missed last week.
So, thank you for being patient with us
and coming back. But we're continuing
our discussion about marriage and
relationship and even for for singles to
learn and glean as much as they can.
This is the time to do it. you will
thank yourself that you took the time
while you were single to learn things
that are so very important for marriage
instead of getting into a marriage and
then like oh let me learn what I need to
do. I mean you can do it that way but
it's harder. [laughter]
It's much harder. Welcome Dr. White.
Good to see you.
>> Good seeing you as well. And
>> how has the beginning of the week been
for you today?
>> It's been a manic Monday. It's been a
manic Monday.
>> Has it been manic Monday?
>> I haven't had such a manic Monday. I
mean, I Yeah. Yeah. It was It was a good
Monday, but there's a lot of things I
had to do, but it wasn't too manic. So,
it was just like
>> in the middle, I guess. [laughter]
>> Yeah. It just kind of like sneaks up on
you and there's so much to do. But
>> look, man, it's it's it's fun to be
doing something you feel passionate
about. That's that is fun. That is
>> Yes. I agree. I agree. Please put in the
chat where you guys are viewing from and
um let us know if this is your first
time watching mental health money
Monday. We want to say a very special
welcome to you, but we like to know
where our v video our v I'm talking now.
I'm not talking well today.
>> Our viewing audience,
>> our viewing I'll say our video audience,
our viewing audience is viewing from. Uh
yeah, please put it in the chat so we
can so we can see where everyone is at.
Um, yes, I love this topic. It's
probably why I became a licensed
marriage and family therapist, even
though we deal with all aspects of um or
many issues um that people deal with
like depression and anxiety and all of
that, but we do specialize in marriage
and relationships and family. And um so
very important um to be able to
either get the help that you need while
you're in a marriage um even to just get
some maintenance. That's very important
too. But like we said earlier, getting
it before you get married, h you can't
even put a price tag on that. like do
the things that you need to do for you
to get yourself ready to be a husband or
a wife and um hopefully the one that is
the person for you is doing the same. So
let's see we have Tacoma, Washington.
>> Y
>> that's Gwendalyn.
>> We got Minnesota.
>> Tacoma is beautiful.
>> I love Mount Reneer. Every time I go it
doesn't matter how many times I've seen
it. It's just it's beautiful.
Okay, we All right, we have Huntsville,
Alabama. Welcome. Just
>> down the street from me,
>> Jason from Asheville, North Carolina. Go
ahead.
>> Yeah,
>> son in Southern California. That's
right. Represent.
>> Yeah. [laughter]
Los
Fresnos, Texas. I was going to say
Fresno, like California, but it's
Fresnos, I guess.
Welcome,
>> Blanca from Los Fresnos.
>> Absolutely.
>> Philadelphia, welcome. Good to see you
here. Yeah, it doesn't look like any
ones. Looks like everybody's been here
before, but let let us tell you um
please put your questions in the chat.
Um you help build this program. We're
here for to answer your questions about
marriage and relationships. Um and
again, even for singles, this is for
you, too. Wow. We already have a
question. All right.
>> It's a comment.
>> Is it a comment? Okay.
>> It's a comment. Um, and before I go
there, in response to what you were
saying,
>> one of the most helpful uh I did see it
on Instagram. All right. Dare I say it.
[laughter] I saw on Instagram and it was
really profound to me because what it
what it talked about was when you see a
couple that's been together for a long
period of time and they're doing well,
meaningfully well in front of and behind
the camera. All right. So, there's in
front of
>> and my goodness can people put on a
show. People can put on a show.
>> Oh, yeah. But I mean like in front of
and behind the cameras when you can't
see them performing
>> and it's still meaningful. It's still
rich.
>> What you're seeing is two people who are
skilled at marriage.
>> Yeah.
>> It's not just a spontaneous love for one
another and you know they're best
friends. And I do think that's really
cool. I think it's really cool when you
see those couples that are genuinely
best friends. Like that's that's a
beautiful thing,
>> right? But but
>> yes
>> but the other way is they they are
skilled at marriage. They've they've
developed the skills
>> of how to communicate that they are
hearing the other person. They've
developed the skill of how to respect
one another. They've developed the skill
of how to love one another. It's a
skill.
>> And the encouraging part of that is
skills can be conditioned. They can be
built. They can be developed.
>> So that's right. If you're not skilled,
there is a chance that you can build the
skills you need. And I heard you saying
for those like people who haven't gotten
married like yet, but they're in their
single,
>> wouldn't it be dope to actually build
the skills so that you can have a
fruitful and and and enjoyable
relationship?
>> Absolutely. Absolutely. Want to say uh
Jason is a first- timer. Uh I think was
that from I forgot where he was from.
went up, but he I think we already said
welcome to him, but he just said it's
his first time. So, welcome Jason.
>> Welcome, Jason.
>> Welcome. All right.
>> Monday.
>> Now, for that comment, you can put the
count the comment back up, Emma. [sighs]
>> Okay. Yes.
>> I heard a divorce lawyer say that
couples should consider taking the
pressure off their spouses by not
demanding that they be all things to
them. I'm from Minnesota.
>> I'll let you take a crack at that. What
are your thoughts, sister? Oh, yeah.
[laughter] I thought you were going to
take the first crack. Um,
well, well, I mean, that's a, you know,
that's a pretty broad statement. Um,
so my first thought is
taking the pressure. So, what do you
what is this? What is I don't know what
the meaning of uh not demanding that
they be all things to them. So all
things, what does that, you know,
include? I mean, it says all. So if
you're saying all, well, of course,
like, you know, they're not God to you,
right? Like God is your God to you. And
who um is ultimately
um
how do I say, your um your conscience,
your support system, all that stuff, you
know, that's not here human here on this
earth. God is is that. But as a human
here on this earth, um I believe that
your spouse, it cannot be all to you,
but they should want to um try to be the
very best for you. Trying to I think
it's like a nice dance that a couple can
do where um you're trying to meet your
husband's needs and your husband is
trying to meet your needs and together
it's a beautiful dance um because you
love each other. It's not like out of a
oh I have to do this for him or oh I
have to do this for her. It's it's
motivated from love and you actually
um enjoy doing it because of love. It's
like with your children like you when
they're little you do what they are
needing because you're in that space to
be able to provide that for them and you
don't do it begrudgingly. You do it
because you love them.
What are your thoughts? Your facial
expression is saying that you're going
in a different direction.
>> That's good. I know. That's good.
[laughter] That's good. You can That
That's really You're You're skilled. Um
I am. Uh
>> that hard,
>> you know. No, you're skilled. You're
skilled. Uh
so where I was going with that is one of
the things that sets people up for
relationship failure is over
expectations.
>> So
>> I would agree. I think a lot of people
believe, you know, it it's like they're
like, "This is the most beautiful person
I've ever met in my life." Right.
>> And so they they they now feel secure.
They're like, "Man, she's gorgeous. I
just she's hot, man. I love it. She does
it for me." Right.
>> Right.
>> And then
it could be at the wedding, you see
someone and you're like, "Oh my
goodness, she's flyer." You know,
>> and this can be a real problem for
people
>> and and beauty and attraction is just
one sliver. It's just one
>> most definitely.
>> There's cooking. There is there is
conversation. There are people who are
just gifted at conversation. There's
child care. There's supporting you
perhaps in a business. There's being
able to listen to you. I mean, there are
like a hundred different things that
humans can be good at. And so imagine
thinking that your spouse is going to be
good at those 100 different things. Like
there are people you're going to
converse with and you may ex you may
experience chemistry. And so for some
people now that's a catastrophe. They're
like, I can't believe I'm talking to
this person and I feel more butterflies
than when I'm speaking to my spouse.
>> Right?
>> Here's the thing. Here's the thing. Your
commitment cannot be based on my spouse
is the best at this thing. It cannot be
based on
>> right. Absolutely not.
>> It has to be based on a conviction and a
decision.
>> Better or worse. Whether you're the best
at that thing or you're not the best at
that thing. Because
if you're not careful, it becomes for
better until better can be gotten
>> as opposed to for better or worse. So,
so I think that that's that's that's why
it's I think it's a really cool idea.
Don't place all these expectations on
your spouse and think that they're going
to be the best in all categories.
They're not. It's impossible.
>> No, absolutely. They're not going to be
the best at all categories. I like to um
like my husband is great
for me and to me, but that doesn't mean
he's good at everything. Does that make
sense?
>> Well, he's human.
>> He's human. So, yeah. Every So, I think
that there's I think that that's your
person because like I feel like like
I'll just use me and my husband again as
an example. I feel like we compliment
each other well. And um but again it's
still he cannot meet
all of my expectations. That's not even
that's not even reality. But he does
enough that makes me very happy.
>> That's awesome. That's awesome.
>> And the parts where he doesn't then we
we talk about it.
>> Well [laughter] well Oh yeah. Let's talk
about that. Let's talk about that. Mhm.
>> When you encounter dissatisfaction in
the relationship, when you when you rec
when you encounter dissatisfaction,
that's the struggle,
>> right?
>> And if you're not if you're not
prepared, it can be a surprise. You're
like, what do I do with this
dissatisfaction? Oh no, I'm falling
[snorts] out of love.
>> Like that's that's the thing. It's like
we're under this impression that if
there's dissatisfaction,
well, then that means it's a bad
relationship, per se. No, you get to
work on that. You get to work on that.
You get to you get to you get to massage
that. And you get to understand we live
on Earth where we're going to have to
deal with the satisfaction. It doesn't
automatically mean I got to toss the um
the the relationship aside because
here's the here's the other truth. If
you jump into another relationship,
guess what you're going to run into?
>> Same thing. Different things, but the
same thing.
>> It's just shaking it up. You're going to
discover. But you will be brought to a
point where you're like, man, this is a
problem, you know, and so that's why
it's so important to deal with this
stuff.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> All right. [sighs and gasps]
Ammer, where you at?
>> I see that there's a
>> All right. Okay. This is this is Thank
you for sharing this first and foremost.
And uh look at this question 3613. We
don't we can't even say a name.
[laughter]
All right. Q. Um so let's see. I believe
the Lord is matching me with a pastor,
but I do feel insecure about being a
pastor's wife. I think church members
expectations and feeling the pressure.
Um do you have advice?
>> Well, well,
>> oh, I thought they were talking to me.
You want to take a stab at that?
>> Oh. Oh. Oh. Well, you would be you're
you're the best student. Yeah. You're
the best student for that question. Go
for it.
>> No, but you can follow up, too.
>> Um,
let's see. So, yeah. Um, yeah, there is
pressure. Oh, by by there is pressure
being a pastor's wife. I mean, if I said
no, that that would not be true. Um, but
this is something that I learned, and
this is 27 years into being a pastor's
wife, is learning how to set your
boundaries for yourself. Um,
and that's again really in any
relationship, but really important to
set your boundaries that the church
understands that you're not the pastor.
They didn't hire you. It's not your job.
They can't um
put things on you be just because you're
the wife or assume that you're going to
do things just because you're the wife,
but you kind of have to set that uh that
standard. Um
I would say right away um because and
then moving on to other churches, it it
becomes easier and easier. Like your
first church, you're like, you know,
what do I do? but truly and to find your
community within that church. But you're
going to have to learn
uh learn the congregation. And I
wouldn't you're not going to be close
friends with the entire congregation,
but you know that you're going to find a
few key people that you feel like you
can trust because it's really important
to have a community for you and your
family within the church. I'll tell you
the next thing is that is not
necessarily your responsibility but it's
his responsibility as the pastor to let
he has to set boundaries like you can
kind of fall your boundaries can kind of
fall in place after his he has to set
the standard to the church and to the
church board and say listen uh I take I
mean okay I can't tell you guys what
days you will take but I know my husband
had to say look I'm going to take Sunday
and Monday off for family time so I'm
not taking church phone calls or I'm
not, you know, doing those type of
things just so that you can because
there's it's easy for the church to take
over your life.
There's so much I could say. So, it's
not even for your relationship and for
the children and it's just for the whole
family. It's important uh for that to
happen. But um yeah, definitely if that
happens to be like you think this is
happening, but if you actually get in
that um
>> you're you know, if you do end up
marrying this person and you do become a
pastor's wife, definitely some
pre-marital counseling from someone who
understands the um lifestyle of a
pastoral couple would be very important.
>> What do you have to say, Dr. White? Um,
first and foremost, you do have a
pastor's wife here. So, if you want to
like ask any more like specifics, um,
yes, you you have you've got a witness.
>> Um, you said like the So, so, first of
all,
>> you know, we can't necessarily customize
our responses because we don't really
know your situation. But
>> you said here, I believe the Lord is
matching me with a pastor. So, if you
were in counseling with me, that's one
of the first things I would say. Hey,
can you share with me? Can you tell me
more about what why you're saying you
believe the Lord is matching you with a
pastor? What is your evidence of that?
What is your um statement? Cuz not you,
not you Q, but some people they ascribe
to the Lord things that are not to that.
No, the Lord didn't tell you to do that.
Um, and so sometimes it's just
interrogating that and and making sure
God really and truly is telling me. And
here's why that's so important. Once you
can be clear, is God talking? Nobody
else has anything to say. [laughter]
It's like it's like you're you're locked
in. If if God if I'm convinced God is
telling me to do something, I'm not
really asking any, you know, more
questions. And you know, I don't know,
maybe I'll get counsel on how to do it,
maybe. But as to whether or not I'm
doing it, I really don't need any
counsel in that direction. God asked me
to do it. Now I'm doing it. So that's
that's the reason that's one of the
things I would ask. But then the next
piece is um but I do feel insecure about
being a pastor's wife. And so it might
be cool to
unpack what about it is making you feel
uncomfortable,
>> right?
>> And this is where some self-awareness is
important. And this is where it's
important to take some time to really
become aware who am I? What are my
strengths that I can bring to this? What
are my weaknesses? And are there things
I can work on? So, for example, if
you're a pastor's wife and you have
social anxiety disorder, you got to work
on that.
>> Yeah.
>> You gota you got to work on that. That's
Yeah.
>> And there are tools to help you work on
that. If you don't like to converse with
people,
>> um you got to work on that.
>> You got to work on that. If you don't
know how to work a room, you got to work
on that. M
>> um if you don't know how to if you don't
know how to set healthy boundaries for
both of you
>> um and so that it's not just a matter of
insecurity but protecting him um you got
to work on that. Uh so I think
it's interesting when we talk about
people of high value and people say,
"Hey, I want to partner with this person
of high value." And it really is a
fishbowl experience.
It's a fishbowl experience. It's like
the relationship is put under so many
pressures. Like there's a lot of people
looking at you. Um there are days you've
just gotten into a rip roaring fight and
now you got to go out there and perform.
You know, now you got to go out there
and function. How do you do that? Um you
you you see then you have to see what
the children go through in that
experience and then how that impacts
you. Um so you can see the emotional
intelligence required.
Uh it's it's exceeding. And so the good
news is though there are skills that you
can build. There are and once you become
aware of, hey, what are my deficits?
Okay, now I know to work on those. What
are my strengths? Well, now I know how
to reinforce those. Um what are the
skills that are essential for a pastor's
wife? So I I think it's a um good
question. But for me, the the thing that
really sticks out is I believe the Lord
is matching me with a pastor. In other
words, I I feel like the Lord is
bringing us together. I would really
want to get clear on that. What are your
thoughts? What are your thoughts?
>> No, no, no. I already said what really I
wanted to say. The way that it was it
was worded. I feel like not that she
thinks like in the future and I'm not
saying you're saying that, but just to
be clear, it seems like she
>> has met the person and God is bringing
them together.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Okay.
>> That's how I took it. Yeah.
>> And so now it's just getting clear. But
yeah, those are some good questions.
>> Okay. All right, we got some great
questions today. Bring them on.
>> Is there a difference from being aside
from God, all things different from
doing all things?
Veronica, you're gonna have to help me
out with this one. Is there a difference
from being aside from God? All things
different from doing all things? I think
she's connecting it to that very first
question like if a or not a question
that comment
where they were like is it that we we
shouldn't expect our spouses to be all
things to us.
>> Dante is brilliant. I mean just
brilliant just that ability to just
>> No. And we we that that's that's
brilliant because I I was not connecting
it to that. I might have just going
>> I think I just think that's just because
the wording sounds similar.
>> Is there a difference?
>> You want to take a stab at that?
>> Let me let me see. Is there a difference
from being
>> I think I kind of already answered it
though.
>> Doing all things. I know it it I think
whether you're saying they're being or
you're saying they're I mean for sure
you can't do it all. Um but as far as
trying to be all things. So I'll give
you an example for example. All right.
Let me take you into the recesses of my
private relationship.
Uh um so let me see. Let me see. Um
I would say what is the thing? Um okay,
my wife does not my wife is not that
crazy about entrepreneurial
thinking. Like she's not that crazy
about it. Um, so
if I if she's going to help me with
something, I have to be very specific
and concrete. And the same thing with my
daughter. They're like, I don't, you
know, just give it to me specific. Like,
what is the specific thing you want me
to do? And once I've got clarity,
they're all over it.
>> They're all over it.
>> Um, so it would be unfair for me to now
try to bring her into, hey, there's a
new concept I'm working on. Can you help
me flush this out?
like it's it's unfair for for for for me
to do that. Now, my collaborator who's
over in um you know, Portugal, oh, we
can sit there and do that all day. I
mean, all day. I mean, she's just she
she understands where I'm going
conceptually.
So, it's that that's an example. it. I
don't try to have her
be with me at these like super
conceptual and you know obscure
theories and stuff like that. No, not
helpful. Um so that's where whether it's
being or it's doing, you can't do all
things,
>> right? Absolutely. Yeah, I think you
covered it. And she said, "My husband is
everything to me, but I don't expect him
to do everything for me." So
yes, I think yeah, I think the way you
answered that was great. I think tag on
to how you answered the first one. I
think that's perfect.
>> Okay.
>> Do you believe in the role of women as
in taking care of the home and the role
of a man as to working and providing?
And is it wrong if the roles are
reversed?
You want to take a first crack? You want
me to take a crack?
>> Um,
no. I to answer it plainly right out the
gate, no. I don't think it's wrong if
the rules are reversed. If we're talking
about
every situation is different. My
husband's a better cook than I am.
So, should I not utilize his skills?
[laughter]
I I I we do utilize his skills. And the
other thing is he loves to do it. He
loves to cook. It's not like it's the
burden. It's not like I don't cook, but
you [clears throat] know, when when the
kids were home,
I would do like he definitely did more
dinner meals than I did. Now I'm doing a
lot of other things now. Now, I'm better
I'm better at
the business, the administrative things
of the home, the business side of
things. I just am naturally better at
that. So, I do more of that. Not that
he's not involved in that at all, but I
do more of that. But, he does more
cooking. And guess what? We're happy
because we know [laughter] he's better
at cooking. I'm better at making sure,
you know, things are getting done
administratively for the family.
I mean, he works and he brings in the
money so I can pay those bills. I work,
too. But I'm just saying, [laughter]
you know, I'm just saying like it's not
it works for us. There's no u now if
you're talking biblically and talking
about submission and going into all of
that, that's a different question,
right? because every that's a different
question. Um, but just specific as far
as roles go, we have found that he's
happy for me to do that and I'm happy
for him to cook and he's happy to cook
and I'm happy to do that. So, that works
for us.
>> Um, I think that was beautifully said.
Um, the answer is absolutely a
resounding uh no. I you know is that
wrong? No.
uh my marriage I think enhanced
significantly
when I adopted a certain premise and
that premise was whatever it takes.
Whatever it takes. My view of a home is
I view it as a firm and I believe uh in
a firm what you do is you set goals for
the firm. You set a vision for the firm
and then as a family
your goal is to work together to get
that
firm's goals realized.
And life is very interesting in
contorting itself and changing itself in
ways that bring different things out of
people. And
I think what you focus on is what's
moving us forward. And and here's why.
You get people who are locked into
he's the man of the home. He makes the
final decision and and this kind of
stuff, right?
>> Like there are categories where I
absolutely have the last word.
Absolutely.
>> Oh, yeah. Most definitely.
>> And there are other areas where I don't
even I don't I don't want the last word
on that.
>> [laughter]
>> I I have no interest in having the last
word on that. No, she has her areas of
dominion where it's like like my last
word will jack everything up, you know?
No, she's got a command of this area and
and that's the other thing like it's
like so so that's really important like
these arbitrary okay well we have this
role and
>> like so where should there be
submission? I think there's submission
to the mission.
That's in my estimation. We need
submission to the mission. What is the
goal? We're all submitted to that
mission. Um there is there are areas
where I do take responsibility because
I'll tell you this, if you guys are
homeless tomorrow, Sister Tante, um
nobody's looking at you.
>> Nobody's looking at you. Everybody's
looking at Bro, you you messed up, man.
your your your family is like what
happened bro?
>> You know and these are some realities
that you just have to be aware of like
>> so this is the reason why there are some
things that you are responsible for
because ultimately people are like you
jacked up. Now obviously they can be
looking at your spouse on some level.
>> Um this is this not exactly a mark of
you know you know a shining spotlight.
No it's it's a reflection on both of you
but it's especially especially the man.
They're like, "Bro, man, what what
happened? You're responsible."
>> So,
>> those are some realities that at times
make people uncomfortable and they want
to say that we're um that we're
identical. And that that to me is the
argument that is a challenge. Um it's
almost like secular culture wants to say
the man and the woman are identical.
We're not.
>> It's fine to say we're equal. We are
equally valuable. Agreed. We're not
identical. We're not identical. And I
think that is the fallacy.
>> Absolutely.
Absolutely. Yes. Please continue to put
your questions on marriage and
relationships in the chat. Um and I
don't know if we have any singles out
there. You know, we welcome your
questions as well. Um so please uh can
we definitely have more time to take
your uh questions and even you know
comments positive comments as well.
>> I'm seeing some things pop up but uh
yeah I think uh going back to that that
question. Oh did something new come up?
Okay
>> Clint uh Clint is on. Welcome Clint.
>> Oh Clint. Hi Clint. I was wondering
where you were. Did you come late Clint?
>> Are you tardy? Are you tardy? Do you
need to go to the principal's office?
>> I know.
>> But before you go there, before you go
there, were you gonna say something?
What were you gonna say?
>> Uh I was just um I was just filling air
time actually. I [laughter]
>> Well, I
>> you know I'm trained in broadcasting,
right?
>> Colonel of truth. I was like, I'm not
going to miss that colonel. What were
you gonna say? No, I was just going back
and to see because there was no there
was no active question. So, I was like,
"All right, let me go back to that one
and see if I could pull some more things
out." But I think you definitely
>> um exhausted uh that one enough.
>> All right. Well, all right. So, Clint,
working together to figure out each
other's role in this cooperative
relationship is very important.
>> Absolutely, Clint.
>> Absolutely. But it's like the ego
disappears when you view the household
as a firm and you see these goals like
dude if I can do it what do I let me let
me do it if I can't do it let me and
I'll tell you this on some level I
believe this is true like when your
family sees you working hard it if they
have hearts
assuming they have hearts it nationally
it it naturally evokes from them it
pulls from them. Hey, let me help this
person. Let me helps this person. It the
the the the display can command
um support. Now, I'm sorry if you're in
a situation where like, dude, are you
kidding? I'm like on I've put it all and
they don't appreciate anything. Okay.
Well, I'm sorry. I'm sorry that's the
case.
>> Yes. And Clint wants us to know. No, he
was early. He says I'm usually punctual.
That's right, Clint. We just didn't see
you say anything in the in the in the
chat. Um, okay. There's a question or
why when we discuss relationships
slashmarriage
are the desire of children such such a
downplayed or minimized aspect of
marrying in your 20s? I don't know if I
understand that question completely. Why
when we discuss relationships/marriage
are the desire for children such a
downplayed or minimized aspect of
marrying in your 20s?
>> So they must be saying that the desire
for children is something that's
minimized or maybe we don't talk about
it enough when we're talking about
getting married in your 20s. I'm not
sure I'm not sure why you say that.
>> Yeah, I'm not quite sure. Maybe they you
to
>> Eno, is it Eno? Yeah. Can you give us a
little bit uh more clarity so we know
exactly what you're asking?
>> Um and then we'll try to answer it.
>> Something about you. How do you get
>> All right.
Okay. This is another This is a comment,
not a question.
As a young single, well, welcome young
single. I'm happy that you're here.
woman. It's becoming very hard to find a
good godly man. I don't know where they
are. Guys, we talked about this. You
know, before we answer that, I'm going
tell you, we are seriously talking. We
are having serious talks about starting
a singles ministry here at LOC Church.
So, I'm just putting it out there, but
but just definitely sign up for alerts
and all of that and watch us so that you
can know when we do that. I
>> not saying they're all here. That's not
the only place you can meet somebody.
That is a that is a struggle. But we've
talked about this before and I'll just
say this and then you can um there's
definitely look like we live in a
different time than we than we used to.
There are
dating sites, Christian dating sites,
Adventist dating sites that I know we've
had couples on here say, "Oh, we met at
a at an Adventist um online dating
site." And they and I'm not saying that
everyone's going to do that, but those
are that's an option. Of course, there's
of course church. You can meet them at
church. Um
yeah,
>> it's
it's it's yeah and and plus and it's God
leading you. Every individual is
different. Every situation is different.
But go ahead, Dr. White.
>> But okay, so first of all, and this is a
cruel comment, but like it's almost like
saying
where is a Rolls-Royce when you need
one, you know? Um or where is where is
what is the most rarest metal? I mean
even be beyond platinum where why isn't
it abundant? Because it's precious.
It's it's precious. Like when and when
you find it, oh my goodness. Like those
of us who find a a great wife know it's
not common. It is it is not common. and
and so so yeah, because it's just
something just so valuable. It's just
such a valuable thing to find a person
who is is high value. So that's not
really the thing. The thing is, you
know, put the energy into preparing and
and being ready. Um, but all that said,
I I do fantasize I do fantasize about
the Mastermind Institute putting
together a singles event
>> where it's like [clears throat]
>> and collab with LMLC church. Could you
collab?
>> I am open to I'm seriously open to a
collab. Seriously open to collab. What
I'm envisioning I'm envisioning like a
training component
>> because to honor the thing that I really
believe that this is a skills-based
thing. So imagine the people commit to a
skills base. So you learn the skills,
but then we bring together, you know,
people in a nice posh setting and they
get like they get dates. They get
whether it's five minute dates. So if
imagine if it was like a yacht and like
you get like that five to 10 dates that
evening and then we figure out how the
ones that really worked for you but to
your point to your point
>> you did you get that idea from the speed
dating concept because you know there's
that speed dating or did you come up
with this concept on your own?
>> No I mean I've seen speed dating before.
I mean I I've I've seen it. So, no, I'm
not really coming up with an original
idea, but to the to the prior point,
like
>> you got to put some intention into this
thing. Like, we got to help the singles,
you know? I know. So, don't you know
people who are just like these are some
beautiful individuals, right?
>> Um, and
>> it's so sad that they don't find their
partner, you know.
>> Um,
>> and uh it's Yeah. Uh, it's it's it's a
it's a real struggle. I I know of a by
the way I know of a young man who is a
very eligible bachelor and it's
obviously it's not me so obviously it's
not I'm very very very married but I
know of a young man he is what
>> you don't even know the age of
>> No not this one like I mean
>> oh okay I thought you were like doing
some online setting up
>> he is what a minute 40 what is he no 37
he's 37 I know of a young eligible
bachelor he's 37 Um, so if you are an
eligible bachelorette
adventist, he really prioritizes
Adventists. All right. So, hit me up at
info@themastermind institute. Info at
the mastermind.
>> Okay. Look at us already doing singles
ministry here.
>> Hit me up at info@the. [snorts]
>> Okay. Okay.
>> So, just FYI.
>> Yes. Okay. Let's see. How do we get rid
of spiritual warfare in your head? I
believe in spiritual armor and I
probably need to repent
repent or brand
loyalty.
>> You're right. So, just to round out the
other one, put a one in the chat if you
guys would be interested in Living Mana
White and the Master Run Institute
collaborating to put together a single
event. Put a one in the chat if you're
like, I would be so interested. Yeah.
and put so interested like like you
would be really excited about this cuz
don't you hate when we go through the
trouble we put together all this stuff
and it's done no we want to know would
you really be interested in us going
through the struggle
>> and um putting together an event like
that would you be interested
>> all right now to you Scott how do you
get rid of spiritual warfare in your
head I believe in spiritual armor and I
probably need to repent repent for brand
loyalty you're going to take the first
crack.
>> No, I'm going to let you.
>> All right. So, you want to you want to
view the mind almost like an ocean in a
sense, right? Um or a pool, more like a
pool. And the question you have to ask
yourself is what are you dumping into
the what are you filling it with? Um
what is the content you're consuming
that is ending up in that pool? If you
fill up your pool with trash, are you
going to be surprised when you see trash
in the pool? When you see maggots and
rats and all this other kind of stuff,
that's what you filled it up with. Um,
and now contrast that with if you fill
it up with beautiful water and you get
the right temperature and you you put
the right chemicals in there so that the
bacteria dies, is there going to be any
surprise that it's a sparkling,
beautiful pool with no mold? Of course
you're not.
So, so, so Scott, the thing you really
have to pay attention to is what are you
pouring into your mind? What are you
pouring in? What are you consuming? That
is absolutely how you insulate your mind
from from wretchedness like that. That
is that is absolutely
um I think it's in Psalms Psalms 1 no
less where it warns you blessed is the
man that walketh not in the counseling
of godly nor standeth in the way of
sinners nor siteth in the seat of the
scorn scornful. That verse just told you
do not walk sit do not walk stand or sit
in the counsel of the ungodly. Don't
walk with them. Don't stand with them.
Don't sit with them. All right? And you
will be blessed. [laughter] It's like
it's giving you hardcore awesome advice.
All right? For you shall be like a tree
that's planted by the rivers of waters.
So the idea being when it's when you're
dealing with the mind, please understand
what are you filling it with. I can't
tell you how many people pick up a book
and start reading it or choose a program
on television and start watching it
without asking without asking the
question, who wrote this book? Who wrote
it? What is their lifestyle look like?
Is it congruent with what I'm trying to
aspire to? You know, what is their
objective? And like it's like me walking
into my dining room right now and seeing
a plate of food and just starting to eat
it.
like and and that's my dining room.
Imagine going imagine just happening
into a place and you see a plate of
food. Would you just start eating it?
You'd be like, "Who is that for? Who
made it? Why did they make it? How long
has it been there?"
>> You know, so things we consume, we
automatically process it.
>> You pick it up, you read the package,
you're like, "Well, what are the
ingredients in here?" But we don't treat
what we view that way. We don't treat
what we consume that way. And then when
we've lost control of our minds, when
we're going to places we have no
business going, we're wondering why
we're going there. Because that's what
we filled our minds up with.
>> And so Scott, we want to you want you
want to fill your mind with the content
with the content that is spiritually
uplifting.
Spiritually uplifting. Now, does that
mean that will ward off all attacks? No.
Because there's also there's also
another reality that Sister Otanti and I
I I think she'll agree with.
Thought impulses you can't control.
There are things there are impulses that
will come into your mind. You can't
necessarily control them. We can debate
where they're coming from, but that's
irrelevant. They come into the mind that
but but you must understand a thought
impulse is an invitation
for you to dwell on it. You can reject
the invitation. You don't have to. Just
because that thought came into your mind
does not mean you have to give it
contemplation and you have to give it
time and space and mental energy. You
can reject it. And how do you reject it
effectively? You choose a better one.
You choose a better thought process. you
know that you get some some kind of
immoral thought about you know I don't
know the opposite sex like it comes in
and you choose to go to you know that
was a spiritually uplifting sermon and
how am I going to apply it to my life
the beauty of the mind is it really
struggles to have two thoughts going at
once it really struggles it has to
choose one well you get to direct it to
the one of your choosing
>> all right Yeah, great great answer. Um,
okay. So, Enoch is asking or saying
clarifying what the question was. I
think that an important reason to
encourage marriage in your 20s because
children are easier to get younger than
older and I read that you're more likely
to have boys when you're younger.
Um, [laughter] so I I don't know about
that. I I've
>> I don't know whether
>> I came across that in uh in in med
school that you're more prone to get
boys when you're younger. I never heard
that. And then the other piece in that
statement is
I I think when you when you marry, you
really should take some time to get to
know one another. I think that's that's
really important. Um, and a lot of
people they one of the things they do is
they travel because from 1 to 5, 1 to 7,
1 to 10, traveling with someone below
10, it can be a real struggle. Can be a
real struggle. It can take the fun out
of traveling for some people. Um, bless
you. Um, and so it can be so cool that
you guys had that bonding time before
the ch child came. So now the other
piece to where it's like I'm not excited
about getting having children in my 20s
is there's a maturation that needs to
take place
and maturation in every way. Maturation
in terms of your thinking, maturation in
terms of your finances, maturation in
terms of your professional growth.
There's a lot of things that it can be
really cool for those things to happen
so that when your kids come into the
picture, it's more stable and and and
you're more you're more mature and ready
and you have more options to give them a
better experience. What are your
thoughts?
>> You you took the words right out of my
mouth, especially the maturity part. Um
I was definitely more mature for the we
call them sets. our younger set got a
more mature version of us than our than
our older set because we were in our
20s, you know. Yeah, we were in our 20s
and um we started having the younger set
like, you know, 30, 31, 32, 33 age and
we were just more mature and just more
seasoned in life. Um so yeah, I mean but
it's not telling anybody when to have
their age their kids. I just there's not
a science but I definitely agree with
you that you can definitely have you can
be more stable in a m mature mature wise
and even financially you know to be able
to not have to stress so much about the
things that you do in your younger 20s.
Okay. In the Adventist home, it says,
"We may always um let's say we may
always bear with friends um infirmities
and with ignorance, but never with his
vices. My boyfriend and I are the same
faith, but I'm stronger spiritually
right now." Okay,
so that's a statement. Okay. So, the
question is,
how do you know when it's time time to
walk away? Okay. I didn't see the Wait,
is that the same I'm confused now. I'm
sorry, guys. That question that's up
now, does that connected to the the
question I just read with the that she's
stronger than the boyfriend right now?
I'm assuming. I don't know. Is that a
connection?
Okay. I think Amber is going to let me
know if that is the same,
but I'll take a But but while we're
while we're waiting, um as a woman, do
um how do I know when it's time to walk
away versus when to support and
encourage my boyfriend before marriage,
for example, with spiritual I think
that's a part of the same question with
spiritual growth and when dealing uh
with an addiction.
Um,
>> man, I wish these people were live. We
got to we got to talk about that. We got
to talk about that. Like, if we could
bring her on right now,
>> I know we could get more detail.
>> We can like and contextualize it a bit
more. You know what?
>> I mean, I would say like like definitely
if a relationship becomes emotionally or
physically abusive,
it's definitely a sign to to walk away.
I mean, this is not marriage. We're
talking about boyfriend,
>> right? Well, I I mean, we're we're we're
you know, so
>> but we can't tell you. You have to walk
away right now. But
>> how about I can tell you things that
would concern me? Okay.
>> Yes. Especially as a a mother or a
father of a young young adult. We both
have young adult children. And if they
were in this situation,
>> woman, how do I know when it's time to
walk away? So, I'm gonna answer this
question. Like, what
>> I mean, I'm considering this as a young
adult. Maybe it's not a young adult. Go
ahead. came to me and she was like, "Um,
Dad, uh, when is it time for me to walk
away versus when is it time for me to
support and encourage?" All right, here
we go, y'all. Here we go. Here we go.
>> I remember one time uh, I had a a close
family member ask me, "Yo, man, when am
I ready to get married? When am I ready
to get married?" And what I shared with
my family member was
you are ready to get married when you
have positioned yourself to provide
when you've when you've positioned
yourself don't don't look at marriage in
terms of what can you get out of it look
at it in terms of what can you bring to
it what can you deliver so here's what I
would say to you man and if you guys can
put your name with your question so that
we can like tell you you know that that
would be awesome or or Maybe not. Maybe
you want to stay anonymous. So, remain
anonymous.
>> Maybe they don't want to.
>> Remain anonymous. Um,
what what I would say is
it's only reasonable that a person would
want to position themselves to add value
to your life. Now, not only is it
reasonable so so it's reasonable for you
to expect that, and in fact, it's
reasonable for you to expect that they
would want to do that for you. That's
that's reasonable. So
that said,
if a person is struggling with something
that removes you as a priority, it would
make sense for them to conquer that
thing and then better position
themselves to be able to bring value to
you,
right? I mean, that that would just seem
simple. So, I'm just saying personally
as a man, um, I know I'm ready for
marriage when I'm ready to add value to
your life. And personally, I wouldn't
feel like I was ready for marriage if
I'm not in a position to add value to
your life. Now, it doesn't mean I will
never be in that position. Just because
I'm not in that position today doesn't
mean I'll never It just means there are
some steps I need to take. There are
some things I need to do that will
better position me to add value to this
person. And one more thing, one more
thing and and please keep this in mind
like this you have to remember with
breakups like when you really and I mean
really love a person
really love them.
It wouldn't hurt you
if there's someone else they could be
with that would make them happy. Now I'm
talking about real love. When you really
care about a person,
you would have to say, you know, it if
if you found someone that would make you
more happy, that's okay with me because
ultimately I'm committed to your
happiness.
>> So, so take what you will from from
that. That's that's my perspective
because ultimately I can't really tell
you provide support, don't provide
support. Not really in a position to
tell you that, but I can tell you um if
my daughter was asking me this question,
I would say when you step into a
relationship, you both you both should
position yourself to bring something to
it. And if you're not in the position to
bring something to it, doesn't make you
bad people. It just means you need some
time. Get in that position then you can
talk about relationship.
>> Yes. Can you marry a person? Okay. Can
you marry a person? You you both live in
separate houses and only come together
for intimacy.
Um
>> so can you can you be married and live
apart? Basically
can you be married and live apart? Okay,
got it. Thank you. Cuz I was going
another direction with that. So that was
brilliant, Dr. White.
>> I received [laughter] that. I received
that. Thank you.
>> Um, okay. It's not okay. That is not I
don't know why I'm I'm spacing on my
answer, but my answer is there. Sorry.
Um, that is absolutely not a a good
thing. I mean I definitely um
if if at all possible I mean it needs to
be possible if you are apart it needs to
be for a very short time but it is not
healthy for a marriage for you to live
apart and only come together uh for
intimacy absolutely not healthy thing a
marriage is more than that you need to
be in the same space and I when I said
like sometimes there's a situation where
you're working towards that maybe the
the the job or school or something's,
you know, having you be separate, but
that should not be long-term by any
means. So, the quick answer is no. It's
not healthy for the marriage.
>> Um,
that's that's an that's interesting. I
would say most of the times it's healthy
to be in the um same space, but I think
there are a lot of people fantasizing
that like take take some take some older
people, right? You know, and ever since
I became um 50, older is now like 90.
[laughter]
>> Exactly.
>> Well, there there are some there are
some people who they are settled. They
have their home and the their partner,
they have their home. Neither one of you
want to sell your home, right? Neither
one of you want to sell your home. You
don't want to feel like you're in your
own space and and so you just being
enjoy being in your own space. Um, I
could foresee how you might have a
relationship where you're like, um,
obviously we got to be in one of those
houses when it's time to have sex. I I
get that. Um, but you're so comfortable
in your own space. I could see how you
might say, "Let's figure out how we can
blend our lives, but we we we want to be
married, but we really enjoy our own
space." So, in that kind of setting, are
you like, "No." [laughter]
I'm like, I was like, "I've never
disagreed with Dr. White so much."
[laughter]
Just because I won't name any names, but
I had a family member exact situation
you're talking about, like exact
situation. And then it was just
comfortable for them and they were an
amazing couple together, but it was just
comfortable for them because they did
exactly what you just stated. But when
it was easy when they had disagreements,
guess what? It was just easy to go to
their own house and not really deal
>> situation
>> with
>> you know what I'm saying? So it's like I
mean I know you're basically saying,
"Oh, you could go to another room. You
could do that in the own house." But no,
when you have your own whole house that
you're paying like a mortgage or you own
it already or whatever, you just go back
to your house like the I just I think
it's hard to build a true marriage
connection even and they were older.
like you stated and then after five
years of living in the two houses
they're just like you know what we got
to choose one house to go to and then
their marriage really flourished and
took off. So
I just don't think that would be the
best at all.
>> One could argue
>> that's just not like this is real
marriage. Like it's like you guys should
have just remained boyfriend and
girlfriend forever if that's what you
wanted to do. Well
>> and and don't and I don't want you to
just get did you just get married for
sex? I'm just saying like cuz you want
to stay in your own places but you come
together for sex in one place but then
you can't live together. Like I'm sorry
that's not
>> Well, I was listening for you to say
that the relationship didn't work out
but it sounds like
>> No, it worked out when they came when
they moved in together. But during that
five years that they did the their own
places, they every week they had
something they were fussing about and
then they would just
because he would come to her house, she
would go to his house. Mainly he came to
her house though and they were married
and then they'd fuss about something and
then he'd just go back to their house
and then they wouldn't talk for like a
week or it was just crazy. It was f
foolishness. But then once they came
together in one house, that kind of
stuff stopped. I'm not saying it was
just the housing, but the housing
situation didn't help having two
separate houses.
>> Yeah. It It's just that with the How
many marriages do you suppose are on the
planet? Um
if there's like 8 billion people,
there must be let's let's conservatively
say there might be a a billion
marriages. Maybe like let's say I don't
know, let's say 500 million. Let's be
conservative. 100 million. How's that?
um 100 million marriages. So like just
100 million scenarios. For me, it's
foreseeable that in a small smattering
of those 100 million marriages,
a two household system works. That that
that's what I'm saying. Now, to your
point, I think in a majority of the
situations, the goal is get in the same
situation and
and and work it out. But there are just
such diverse things happening that
>> yeah I mean I would never be like
absolutely never. There's absolutely no
situation but I have just say but I've
just experienced that that's it's not
the best for the majority of situations
but I'll never say absolutely never
never. And I want to say to Veronica she
says I know an older couple that's been
married for decades but have been living
in separate bedrooms. Is that very
different? Um, no. I don't I don't um
think that that's good either. I
definitely when I'm working with
couples, um I'm definitely encouraging
them to get in the same room.
>> What about when one of the couple
members snores?
>> I know you're going to say snores. I
think they then I encourage them to to
go to I think an ENT to see if they have
sleep apnea.
>> You know what cured my snoring?
>> Did you get a CPAP?
>> I got a CPAT machine.
>> That's what I was saying. I know. That's
what everybody that's that's what
everybody need. Well, let me know. I'm
not a doctor. [laughter]
>> But you should go and check it out for
sure.
>> Dude, it it changed the game for me. It
changed the game.
>> I know. I know.
>> But it was so hard for my spouse. It was
so hard for my spouse before.
>> I could imagine. I could imagine. Um,
somebody else said something and I was
going to say, but we'll Oh, I know what
I was going to say. I was just going to
tag on to that. The reason why I don't I
always encourage my couples if there's
some reason why they're sleeping apart
uh that they need to come together even
if they're in the same house is because
honestly I mean it sounds crazy but you
wouldn't know how many times I've had to
uh prescribe sex for homework because
there was just not enough of that
happening in the marriage like a couple
of times a year or do you see what I'm
saying? like those type of things like
you cuz they're just like, "Oh, we're
busy and we're stressed and then we're
just tired when we get home." And
>> so it doesn't help when you're in two
separate rooms or not in the same bed.
So,
>> isn't it that's a whole another We
should do a whole program on that, but
go ahead. cuz I'm like, isn't it
interesting how how like
people
have these like sexual,
you know, proclivities and experiences
where it's like they're just running
into like casual sex, right? But then
>> they get married, it's all
>> you get married or like you're in
marriage for a while, the high
percentage of relationships that are
sexless,
>> right? It's like it's so it was so
interesting because it's like it's the
it's so counterintuitive. It's like
you've been fighting for this
>> now. time, right? You know, you know,
have as much as you want, but
>> but but the interesting thing is like
and it's the courtship period that
really needs to be sexless because
>> right
>> now you're going to actually see you get
courtship gives you a front row seat to
what your partner will be like when
they're tested.
>> Like this is this is the thing people
miss about courtship. It is during
courtship. It's a unique period in the
relationship where you get to see how
your partner, potential suitor,
>> handles being being sexually tested.
>> You get to see it.
>> Um, and so a lot of people, they rush
past it. They rush past it. And you
you've missed the opportunity to get a
front row seat at how they handle sexual
temptation. Right. Absolutely.
>> And rather than growing together and
learning, okay, well, this is what you
do, this is what you don't do, this is
how you set boundaries, and they grow
through that period, it's like they
start having sex, and they miss the
opportunity to see what each other, it's
a front row seat to how each other
handles sexual temptation. That's what's
unique about courtship.
>> We have time. We're all out of time, but
we have one more question, and you guys,
please save your questions for next
time. But this one is our last one. The
one you see there on your screen says,
"I don't have a desire to have children
and I don't uh think I really want them.
Is that wrong?"
>> Well, I'll give you my question.
>> Yeah, I'll give you my experience. Last
trick one. So, I remember my wife and I,
we were like, um, we're like, we don't
want to have children. Uh we were I
think I'll be honest we had really
really high standards for when you have
kids and so you're like h I don't want
to do it. Uh well lo and behold God had
other plans [laughter]
>> got
plans and and we had yeah we we ended up
having our daughter.
She is the best part of our
collaboration like She is the best part
of our collaboration, the best thing in
our um lives.
>> So, it it amazes me how
it can be a situation where you don't
want something and it actually delivers
to you something you didn't even know
you wanted or needed.
>> Yeah.
>> So, that's that was my experience with
that. Now that doesn't mean that would
be your experience with it, you know,
but that's my personal experience with
it.
>> It it gave me something. It gave me one
of the best things in my life. It
stretched me. It taught me about being
selfless.
>> Absolutely. And I'll tell you what else
uh last chick
uh we are rapidly entering into a phase
an age where everyone we know and love
would have e either died or is in the
same situation that we're in.
>> So you can see how much we're going to
be able to help one another. We are
rapidly getting to that phase where
people before us, the people who the
adults that love they they all have
passed, they all have died and the
remaining people that know us and love
us, we're like the same age except
>> our children.
>> Yeah.
>> Our children. We are entering into that
phase where the beauty of a child is
they now have entered into their
maturity. They've entered into their
power. they've entered into their
influence in a moment where you are
vulnerable.
>> You're vulnerable and and they and
they're there and they can offer you
that care. That that's the beauty of
children. That's the beauty of investing
in the future.
>> Um so that's something to keep in mind
for those who say, "Hey, I don't want to
have children."
>> Yes. And to answer the question, and
Veronica, yes, you're right. Childhood
trauma can cause you to not want to have
kids. Doesn't have to be childhood
trauma, but it's possible. Uh just for
her comment is just FYI, I think it
that's just fine. Um I think it and it
is like it's not a sin not to have
children by no means. Like it's just
it's just not. However, no correct.
>> I think Ricardo and I are both talking
from a personal level that the blessing
that it has been
>> well I'll speak for myself. the blessing
it's been for me
>> um that how it has just been a part of
God's plan for my life and to help I
believe grow me and draw me closer to
him through my children and my children
are a blessing especially now that
they're adults man they are a blessing
they [snorts] really are a blessing
>> you know what's funny when people think
about children right they think about
like that period where they're the
biggest pain frankly
um where it's like they're difficult and
they're challenging. It's like from like
0 to 10
>> hard. I mean it's
>> where you where you leaving teenage out
I think
>> but now teenage it it becomes difficult
in another way because
>> in another way having children is that
whole thing and anyway don't those
chromosomes form I know I'm totally
interrupting you but
>> until those chromosomes form at tw
[laughter]
>> at what age are you saying they form?
No, I was saying I'm sorry and I
interrupted you. I'm so bad for that.
you had a whole thought you were saying,
but I just want to say like no how
children at the you know when they're
young and you're not sleeping when
they're babies are so cute and you love
them but you're not sleeping and you
know all that stuff and then you get
through that then they're toddlers and
then they're it's like they have all the
stages there's blessings and it's hard
and it's blessings and it's hard but
when the chromosomes they say at 24
you're the doctor so but I believe
that's what it is at 24 the chromosomes
form and then you're like oh you're such
a mature delight to be around.
[laughter]
>> It's straight up true. Like my daughter,
my daughter, she helped me to check in.
She helped me to check in. Like it's
just little simple things. And then of
course I could do it for myself, right?
But like she helped me check. I'm like,
man, that's dope. You [laughter] know, I
don't even need to check. Anyway, my
point was a lot of times people focus on
the 0ero to 10 like that period where
you've got to pour into them where
they're dependent on you and not
realizing dude that's actually a small
phase of it. It's very demanding. It's
very difficult. That's true. But that's
a small phase of it and it and it it
moves pretty quickly where they're out
of that and they're into their 10 to
20s. Now they're in that phase where
they don't even want to hang out with
you now. Like before you had to monitor
every moment. By the time they're
hitting 10, 15, they don't even want to
hang out with you.
>> They're like, "Okay, bye mom. Bye, Dad.
>> Drop me off. Drop me off over here.
Don't you know?" Oh my goodness.
[laughter]
It's crazy. Um but but the point is
being sometimes we characterize it as if
the whole thing will be that like you
wouldn't like to have a young person.
You wouldn't like to nurture that
person. You wouldn't want to mentor that
person. You don't want to get to observe
a person, a a human being evolve. You
got to understand as a man what it's
like to actually see a young lady
evolve.
>> Yeah.
>> You don't know anything about it
honestly. Like I mean I guess some
people have sisters and maybe but for
you as a parent to watch a young lady
evolve
>> Yes.
>> It's it's powerful. It's like
>> it is beautiful. It's hard for you to be
as disrespectful. You know, it's it's
it's on some level anytime you're
looking at a a woman subsequently,
you're like, "That's somebody's
daughter.
>> That's somebody's daughter." Because you
got to see that. You got to see it. So,
anyway, that
>> absolutely. Absolutely. We had a great
time. We definitely made up our time for
being late. So, that is that's wonderful
for everyone. and wanted you to know, I
don't know if you were looking in the
chat, but you had at least six or seven
people say they would absolutely love to
have that collab happen. So, if you want
to give your email where you can follow
up and we have to talk about this
because we just came up with this idea.
Well, I'm sure you were thinking about
it for your mastermind institute, but I
threw in the collab with LMOC. So,
you know what? You're muted, so we can't
hear.
I said, "I would love to collaborate."
Yes. With this.
>> Okay. So, if you want to put out your
email now or if you just want them to
wait until we can send
>> info at the Mastermind Institute. Info
at the Mastermind Institute. Just so you
can say, "Hey, I'm dialed in. I'm
interested."
>> Um, I would I would be super excited to
to participate in something like that.
>> That would be a great blessing for our
church and for the singles out there.
>> Absolutely.
>> So, yes. Well, thank you all of you uh
for joining us this evening. Your
questions, your comments, your presence
was a blessing. Thank you, Dr. White.
And we wish you all a good evening.
Until we see you next time, God bless.
>> Take care. Byebye. of the night.